truckstop.com 2019-06-05

# Privacy Policy - Truckstop.com

Last modified: September 29, 2016

Truckstop.com collects information about you when you access and use our websites, mobile applications, content, products and services (collectively, the “Services”) and through other interactions and communications you have with us.  Our Services are provided by Internet Truckstop Group LLC, a Delaware limited liability company, located at 222 N. Plymouth Ave., New Plymouth, ID 83655, and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Truckstop.com”).  This Privacy Policy applies to information collected and used by Truckstop.com unless any of its websites, mobile applications, content, products and services indicate they are subject to a separate privacy policy.  In this Privacy Policy, the words “including” and “include” mean “including without limitation.”

Protecting individual privacy is important to us.  This Privacy Policy is intended to notify you, or in the case that you represent a business entity, you and that business entity (“you”), of the type of information that we may collect from users of the Services and to generally summarize how we use and protect that information.  Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it.  BY ACCESSING AND USING THE SERVICES, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS SET FORTH IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SERVICES.

THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

_Information You Give Us_  
We collect information you provide directly to us, including personally identifiable information you submit to complete a transaction or to receive information you have requested, such as by contacting us or registering to receive product announcements, updates and notifications, as well as content you submit in connection with your access and use of the Services.  This information may include your name, email address, mailing address and telephone number.  We may also collect financial information, including credit card numbers, associated card data and tax identification numbers, in the event you register an account and purchase Services from us.  Your payment information is collected and processed by a third party vendor and is not stored or accessible by us.

_Information We Collect From Your Use of Our Services_  
When you access and use our Services, we collection information about you that includes the following general categories:

  * _Usage and Preference Information_ : We collection information about how you interact with our Services, including the types of Services provided, time spent using the Services and other related transaction details. When you access the Services, we may use a web server log to automatically track and collect certain non-personally identifiable information, such as your Internet protocol (IP) address, referral pages and pages viewed, access times and other relevant statistics.  We also may use common information collection tools like pixel tags (also called beacons or clear gifs), which are small files installed on or called by a webpage or application, to retrieve certain information about your browser or device, including device type, operating system, browser type and version, website visited, time of visit, referring website, IP address and other similar information.  Another common identification technology we may use is cookies, which are small files placed on your computer’s hard drive or mobile device, to help recognize unique users and monitor general traffic and use trends.  Cookies help us to understand how you use and navigate our Services and, in turn, how we can make our Services more user friendly.
  * _Device Information_ : We may collect information from and about your mobile device, including the hardware model, operating system and version, software and file names and versions, preferred language, device identification number, serial number, device motion information, mobile network information, device’s telephone number, timestamp, location and stored cookies information.
  * _Log Information_ : When you interact with our Services, we collect server logs, which may include information like device IP address, access dates and times, application features or pages viewed, application crashes and other system activity, type of browser and the third party site or service you were using before interacting with our Services.
  * _Location Information_ : When you use our Services for load tracking, we collect precise location data about the trip from the application used by the driver. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP address.

_Third Party Information Collection  
_ When you use our Services, certain third parties may use automatic information collection technologies to collect information about you or your device.  These third parties may include your mobile device manufacturer, your mobile network provider and analytics companies.

The information these third parties collect may be associated with your personally identifiable information or they may collect information, including personally identifiable information, about your online activities over time and across different websites, applications and other online services websites.  We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used, and we are not responsible for their practices.  We encourage you to visit the third parties’ websites to learn more about their privacy policies.

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

The information we collect may be used to provide, maintain, protect, help improve, develop new functionality, administer and personalize our Services, provide product and service information, fulfill transactions or requests made by you and give you notices about your account and when application updates are available.  The information may also be used to carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection, and for analytics, industry and market research and such other purposes consistent with our legitimate business needs.  Further, we may use certain information for the purpose stated at the time of your disclosure.

Please note that we may share your personally identifiable information with third parties we use to support our business or with whom we have a business relationship and among each of our affiliated companies.  We may also disclose your personally identifiable information:

(i)  If we are required to do so by law or legal process (such as a court order);

(ii)  In response to a request by law enforcement authorities; or

(iii)  When we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.

When you agree with another user of our Services to provide load tracking data to the other user, we will provide location information to the user during the applicable trip.  By agreeing to provide load tracking data to the other user, you expressly:

(i)  agree to permit Truckstop.com’s applications to access location services through the permission system used by your mobile operating system;

(ii)  consent to Truckstop.com’s use of location-based services, disclosure of your location data to the other user of Truckstop.com’s Services with whom you agreed to provide load tracking data and disclosure of your location data for the reasons described above about how we may share your personally identifiable information with third parties; and

(iii)  agree to defend, indemnify and hold us and our employees, contractors, officers and managers harmless from all liabilities, claims and expenses, including attorneys’ fees, arising out of or resulting from you disabling the collection of location information by changing the location settings on your mobile device.

We do not rent, sell or trade any personally identifiable information and will not share your personally identifiable information with any third party except as set forth above.  However, we will from time to time contact you about our own or other companies’ goods and services that we think may be of interest to you.  We reserve the right to transfer your personally identifiable information in the event we sell, merge or transfer all or a portion of our equity, assets or business.

We may disclose your non-personally identifiable information publicly or to third parties without restriction to, for example, show trends about the use of our Services, as we do not deem such information private or confidential.

YOUR CHOICES

_Account Information  
_ You may correct your account information at any time by logging into your account.  If you wish to cancel your account, please contact us as set forth in this Privacy Policy.  Please note that in some cases we may retain certain information about you as required by law or for legitimate business purposes to the extent permitted by law.  For instance, if you have a standing credit or debt on your account, or if we believe you have committed fraud or violated our Terms and Conditions, we may seek to resolve the issue before deleting your information.

_Rights Concerning Your Personally Identifiable Information  
_ If you provide us with personally identifiable information, you have the following rights with respect to that personally identifiable information to:

(i)  Review the personally identifiable information that you have supplied to us;

(ii)  Request that we correct any errors, outdated information or omissions in the personally identifiable information that you have supplied to us;

(iii)  Request that your personally identifiable information not be used to contact you;

(iv)  Request that your personally identifiable information be removed from any solicitation list that we use;

(v)  Request that your personally identifiable information be deleted from our records; and

(vi)  Opt out of being solicited by us.

If you request that your personally identifiable information be deleted from our records, there may be a brief delay in our processing that request while we verify that the request is valid and originates from you as opposed to an unauthorized third party. If you request that your personally identifiable information be deleted, we reserve the right to terminate any account you have registered with us or limit your access to the Services.

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

_Location Information  
_ If you initially permit the collection of precise location from your mobile device per the permission system used by your mobile operating system, you can later disable it by changing the location settings on your mobile device.  This may limit your ability to use certain features of our Services.  Additionally, disabling the collection of precise location from your mobile device will not limit our ability to derive approximate location from your IP address.

_Cookies  
_ With most Internet browsers, you can erase or reject cookies, or set your browser to prompt a warning whenever a cookie is sent.  It may be possible to refuse to accept mobile cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your mobile device.  If you choose to refuse or remove cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services.

OPTING-OUT  
If you have registered for product announcements, news or updates, we will use your personally identifiable information to fulfill your request.  You may stop receiving any electronic communications from us, including our newsletter, at any time by clicking on and completing the opt-out link provided at the bottom of the applicable email.

HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION  
The security of your personally identifiable information is important to us and we take reasonable precautions to protect it.  Information that is collected that is deemed to be confidential will be collected using secure socket layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts data sent from your browser to our servers.  This data is then also encrypted in our databases, and only accessible by authorized staff within our organization.  Additionally, most Internet browsers also offer their own security features that enable end users to control how their transmissions are protected.  Please remember, however, that any personally identifiable information you send to us via the Internet is subject to the risk of unlawful interception by third parties, and that no method of safeguarding information is 100% secure.  Further, please note that, in our discretion, aggregated information that contains no personally identifiable information may not be treated as private or confidential.

CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 13  
The Services are not intended for use by children, and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.  If you are under the age of majority in your place of residence, you may use the Services only with the consent of or under the supervision of your parent or legal guardian.  If we learn that we have received any information directly from a child under the age of 13 without first receiving his or her parent’s or legal guardian’s verified consent, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or his or her parent or legal guardian) to inform the child that he or she cannot use the Services and subsequently we will delete that information.  If you believe we might have any personally identifiable information from or about a child under the age of 13, please email us at support@truckstop.com.

AFFILIATED COMPANY WEBSITES  
To the extent our Services contains links to any other websites operated by us, our partners or affiliates (each an “Affiliated Company Websites”), please check the individual Affiliated Company Website for its applicable privacy policy, which may differ from this one, depending on the specific nature of that Services and the transactions taking place there.  If an Affiliated Company Website has its own privacy policy, the provisions of that policy will control, to the extent of any conflict with this Privacy Policy.

EXTERNAL LINKS  
For your convenience, we may provide links to websites that are external to us.  We do not operate these external websites, have no control over them and are not responsible for the privacy practices or contents of such external websites.  If you chose to visit any external website, understand that your use of such external website is subject to their terms of use and privacy practices.  Please familiarize yourself with their privacy policies and information collection practices.

CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY  
Our Privacy Policy may change at any time.  If there is a significant change in the information we collect or our other privacy practices, we will provide you notice through the Services or by another means.  Your continued access and use of the Services after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check our Privacy Policy periodically for updates.  Your access and use of the Services following the posting of any revised Privacy Policy will be deemed acceptance of the revised policy.

LOCATION OF OUR SERVERS  
If you are visiting our Services from outside the United States, please be aware that our Services and the servers that host it are located in the United States and any information or data you provide, including personally identifiable information, will be transmitted to the United States and subject to access requests by U.S. authorities.

CONSENT  
By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to our collection and use of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

GENERAL  
This Privacy Policy is a part of our Terms and Conditions. The terms set forth in our Terms and Conditions, including your agreement with respect to the governing law and venue in the event of a dispute, apply to this Privacy Policy.

ENFORCEMENT OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND CONTACT INFORMATION  
If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or believe we have not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please contact our VP of Technical Operations at [support@truckstop.com](mailto:support@truckstop.com) or by mail at:

Truckstop.com  
Attn: VP of Technical Operations  
Re: Privacy Policy  
222 N. Plymouth Ave.  
P.O. Box 99  
New Plymouth, ID 83655
